gov.nf.ca 2014-04-03

# Disclaimer/Copyright/Privacy Statement | Government of Newfoundland and Labrador

Francais

The following policies govern the operation and management of this Web site:

## Disclaimer

Information on this Web site is provided as a public service by the Government of Newfoundland and Labrador. We cannot guarantee that all information is current or accurate. Users should verify the information before acting on it. Although we make every effort to ensure that all information is accurate and complete, we cannot guarantee its integrity.

The use of this Web site is subject to the following terms and conditions and constitutes the user's agreement to those terms and conditions. Information on this web site is provided by government solely for the user's information and it is provided without warranty, guarantee, or responsibility of any kind, either express or implied. The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador and its employees will not be liable for any loss or damages of any nature, either direct or indirect, arising from use of the information provided on this Web site or information provided at any other site that can be accessed from this site.

Links from this site to other sites are presented as a convenience to users. The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador, does not accept any responsibility for the content, accuracy, reliability, or currency found on external sites.

## Copyright

The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador is the owner of copyright in all information found on this Web site unless otherwise stated.

Where the Government of Newfoundland and Labrador is the owner of copyright in information on this Web site, government hereby grants permission for the information of this web site to be used by the public and non-government organizations. Persons and organizations using this information agree to indemnify and save harmless the Government of Newfoundland and Labrador against any claims or actions of any kind or manner resulting from its use.

The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador uses multi-media, i.e. graphics, audio and visual materials, on this Web site with permission of third party copyright holders. Reproduction of such materials is not permitted.

## Privacy statement

### Introduction

The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador maintains this website to help you obtain information about its programs and services. The Provincial Government is committed to protecting the privacy of individuals and organizations who visit this website, in compliance with the _Access to Information and Protection of Privacy (ATIPP) Act._

A departmental website may have a different privacy statement, depending on the nature of its site. You should review a website's privacy statement each time you submit personal information.

In order to make our site more useful to the public, our web server automatically collects and saves a limited amount of information concerning your visit. The information collected is not personal information and does not link to individuals. This information includes:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address (e.g. 123.45.67.890)

  * Browser type and version (e.g. Netscape 8.0, Explorer 7.0)

  * Page(s) visited

  * Date and Time of page(s) visited

### Definition of personal information

Personal information means _recorded_ information about an _identifiable_ individual, including the individual's name, address or telephone number. The _ATIPP Act_ outlines several examples of personal information [ http://assembly.nl.ca/Legislation/sr/statutes/a01-1.htm ](http://assembly.nl.ca/Legislation/sr/statutes/a01-1.htm)

### Collecting personal information

The only identifiable personal information collected by this website is information you give voluntarily (e.g. using a government online service or submitting a complaint, comment or feedback electronically). Government considers the personal information you provide through this website confidential. This information is collected in compliance with the _ATIPP Act_ and will only be used by authorized staff to fulfill the purpose for which it was originally collected, or for a use consistent with that purpose unless you expressly consent otherwise This information is not disclosed to other public bodies or individuals except as authorized by the _ATIPP Act_.

If you choose not to use the Internet to provide personal information through this website, you may still be able to access government services by telephone, fax, mail, or in person. Not all options may be available in every situation.

### Security

Section 36 of the _ATIPP Act_ states that Government shall protect personal information by making reasonable security arrangements against such risks as unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure or disposal. Security measures are integrated into the design, implementation and daily operating practices as part of Government's ongoing commitment to protecting your personal information.

### Links to other websites

This website may include links to websites operated by other public and/or private sector organizations. The Government of Newfoundland and Labrador is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of external websites.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file placed on your hard drive (with your permission) by a web page server. Cookies are used on this website to identify return visits to a web page but are not used to collect statistical or personal information. You may change the settings on your web browser to deny cookies or warn you of the deposit of cookies.

Please direct any questions regarding this privacy policy or the _ATIPP Act_ to the Access to Information and Protection of Privacy (ATIPP) Office.

<http://www.atipp.gov.nl.ca/>

If you have a complaint or concern about your personal information, please contact the relevant public body. If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction, the _ATIPP Act_ provides a mechanism for independent review by contacting the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner.

<http://www.oipc.gov.nl.ca/>

For more information:

**E-Mail:** [info@mail.gov.nl.ca](mailto:info@mail.gov.nl.ca)

**Regular Mail:**  
Communications Branch, Executive Council   
10th. Floor, East Block  
Confederation Building  
St. John's, NL  
A1B 4J6  
Attention: Doris Walsh
